(BELLA) JINGBING HUANG

Tel: 778-988-8174 Email: bellahuang1012@gmail.com https://bellabellahuang.github.io/

A fast learner who has enthusiasm in building big data solutions with great experience and knowledge in AWS, Python and Snowflake. I have almost 3 years of working experience in designing and building data pipelines for millions of daily processing data.

Work Experience

Data Warehouse Developer | BroadbandTV, Vancouver

2018.10 - Present

- Implemented a generic solution for data migration from MySQL to Snowflake
- Developed an efficient and reliable system to collect millions of video and channel data on a daily basis
- Designed and built ETL/ELT pipelines to move large amount of data throughout Snowflake
- Designed and built slack bots for internal data access in Lambda and Python to increase work efficiency
- Created APIs to secure user login with MFA for the internal claiming tool using Cognito and API Gateway
- Built reusable components to export data from Google Drive using Docker and Python
- Automated monthly import workflow with Shell and Python scripts to reduce average time by 50%
- Be responsible to operate monthly partner payment process to ensure data accuracy
- Maintained the revenue process system in Spark and Python to meet business needs
- Worked with the finance team and other relevant stakeholders to perform regular data reports or audits
- Trained and mentored new team members with patience

Intern | City of Sarnia, Ontario

2018.4 - 2018.6

- Led a team of four to set up a video surveillance security system in Linux environment
- · Set up master-slave replication for the recording database in MySQL
- Installed GitLab in a local ubuntu server and documented the project details in Markdown

Skills

- 2+ years' hands-on experience on AWS (S3, SQS, Firehose, Lambda, API Gateway, Cognito)
- 3+ years' experience in **Python** and 2+ years' experience in **Java, C#** and **Bash**
- 2+ years' experience in **Snowflake** and solid knowledge in relational database
- Extensive experience in ETL/ELT pipeline design and development
- Proficiency with SQL, Linux, Git, Spark, Docker and Serverless

Education

Computer Software and Database Development | Lambton College, Canada

Post-secondary Certificate

Hands-on experience in building system in JAVA and database design

2016.9 - 2018.6

Bachelor of Information Management | Guangdong Pharmaceutical University, China

2010.9 – 2014.6

Solid knowledge of information system design and programming skills in JAVA and C#

Certificates

- Udacity Data Engineering Nanodegree
- IoT & Modern Web Specialist Certificate
- MongoDB for Java Developers Certificate
- MongoDB for DBAs Developers Certificate